Hello again.
So here we are in this new section about analog aspects of the NFC communication.
First part we will be talking about the standards.
Proximity cards are all proprietary.
This is also the case of the memory based first generation of contactless smart cards.
This means that there is no compatibility between the readers of a specific brand and the cards of another
brand.
Contactless smart cards are covered by the ISO 14,443 and ISO 50,693 standards.
These standards define two types of cards, A and B, each with different communications protocol.
So these standards, as I said, define two types of cards.
Which typically have a range up to ten centimetres.
The related ISO 15,693 for vicinity cars.
Standard typically works up to a longer range of 100cm.
The reality is that ISO 14 443, as well as ISO 15 693, can only be fully implemented on microprocessor
based cards.
The best way to check if a technology meets ISO standards is to ask the manufacturer if it can be emulated
on other devices without any proprietary hardware.
The standard for proximity cards and couplers.
Pics and Pcds is ISO 14,443, which is divided into four layers.
The first one is the ISO 14,143 one, which covers the physical aspects of the card.
This layer describes the physical part of the receiver and the size of its antenna.
Second one is the ISO 14,443 two that defines the field level and bit level modulation.
This layer in fact, deals with the frequency at which the transmitter and receiver should operate.
In the case of NFC.
It's 1350 six megahertz.
This is the carrier frequency of the NFC.
We also talk about the signal, the transmission rate, etc., etc..
There are two variants, A and B, which differ on the modulation and the binary encoding used.
The third one is the ISO 14,443 three, which tells how the bits are assembled in bytes and then in
frames.
There are two options.
ISO 14,443 type A that chooses on off keying modulation, okay and Manchester coding.
However, ISO 14,443 type B card uses a 10% amplitude shift keying modulation and also nrzi coding.
The coupler or the PCD shall implement both types, but the card or pack may choose to implement only
one of them through the next.
Next sessions, I'm going to present to you these different types of modulations and coding.
More than that, in this layer three, we address the creation of communication between the transmitter
or PCD and the receiver or pack, and the principle of anti-collision, which makes it possible to manage
the case of several receivers which are found at the same time in the magnetic field.
And finally the ISO 14,143 four, which stops both types with a block oriented transport protocol.
Not far.
Not far from T equal one protocol of ISO 7008 16 dot three.
This protocol is often referred to as T equal CL, short for transport equal contactless.
Although this name does not appear officially in the standard.
So this layer also deals with the protocol used in the transmission of information.
It describes the data format and communication during a transaction, etc., etc..